This morning I
woke up to
snowfall and couldn't
shake the feeling
that I was living in a little
snow globe from a
fairy tale world.  These
simple joys
help my
heart stay
light during the
long, dark winters.
It's interesting how such a
harsh time of year can
be so
beautiful and refreshing at the same time.
A call to relax
your body and get cozy
with the forest
dwellers.  I had
no idea that within a few
hours this pleasant
snowfall
would turn into a
winter storm that would
lock
me in my house for days,
watching ice
hit the kitchen window and
gusts of wind fiercely
whipping snow off the
trees.  I had no
choice but to
stay put,
which is of course one of
my favorite things to do.
I love spending time
at home, making small
decorations, and baking
goodies.  Jane
Austen once said, "
There is nothing better
than staying at home
for real
comfort."  And I can't
disagree with that.  Oh
no, I think I
burned the cornbread
.  I burned it.
Oh no.  This week I
had some free
time and spent it
juggling household
chores and creative
projects, doing everything
with the intention of
prioritizing rest
and recovery.  If
you watched my
last video, you
know that this year
I'm aiming to
appreciate myself more and
develop
confidence.
It has been a challenging but
rewarding journey so far.  How are
you doing?  When I
mention the word "
self-love," it can
have many different
interpretations.  I know
some people see it as
something special to
treat themselves to, others
as setting
healthy boundaries, and still
others as
focusing on
relaxation.  All of these
things sound great.
I personally like to
think of
self-love as the practice of
proper
self-respect and valuing
one's soul.  If I'm
trying to be
more confident, I need to
show
respect for myself by
honoring my
decisions and
supporting myself
when necessary.
I need to
respect myself
enough to
work on
learning
positive
self-talk
.  That's what I've
been working on this year.
This may not be a
typical way to show
self-love, but it has
helped me
feel so much
better, and I think one
of the reasons is that
I'm trying to
make a permanent
internal change, not a
temporary external one.  I
remember when I was
younger, hearing my
friends joke about the
power of retail therapy
or pampering when
you're not feeling your
best.  I'm
sure these things
can be very
useful.  All people are
different.  And I also
think it's worth
working on changing
your beliefs about
yourself if they're
negative.  Changing
from within is also a
powerful and extremely
important tool
for feeling more
self-fulfillment.
At least, that's what I want
my story to
cover this year
.  I think the
hardest part about
learning to
appreciate yourself and
love who you are is the
invisibility of the
process.  You can't
prove to other people
that you have innate
value.  They just
need to know that it is
so.  It is impossible
to get something from the outside
that will make everyone
love you, never
doubt you, and never
hurt you.
You need to live with
awareness of your
value and simply
know that it exists.  You can't
rely on
others to
constantly
confirm this.  I don't
want
someone else to write my story.  I
want to create it myself
.  And this year I
hope you will
do the same.
Hello everyone.  I
realized that probably the
last few times
I've talked to
you on camera, I've been wearing
this dress, and I
swear, I'm recording
on different days.  It's just
one of the few
things that still
fits me, and it's also a
color that I really
like.  That's why I
wear it so often.
I don't have many dresses
that really
fit, but my mom
recently gave
me this one and I
really like it.
She knows my
tastes very well.  She bought it
secondhand.  I
mostly wear
leggings and sweaters, and I
think that will be a
theme for the next
few months.  I
wanted to say a
huge thank you for the
wonderful response to my
last video.  I
received so many
interesting stories,
feedback, and ideas
shared by
many people.  It was
quite interesting,
enjoyable and very
inspiring.  I see that
self-doubt is something that
many
people have.  I think it
depends on your
experience or
tendency to be
too
demanding of yourself.  When I
found myself at my
lowest points, where there
was so much
doubt, so much
shame, so much
cruelty to myself,
truly believing that there was
no way to become
better, to feel
better, to become the
person I wanted to
be.  I associated
that time with disintegration and
brokenness, considering
it something very
negative.  However,
looking back, I
no longer see it that way.
And I hope that
anyone who has been in a
vulnerable state
might find it helpful
to look at it the same way
.  It wasn't the
end of anything.
In fact, it was the
beginning of something
quite beautiful.  And
I think if we
took our
worst moments
in that way, we could
be kinder to
ourselves.  I
think when you
reach that point
where you feel
overwhelmed by a
problem or something you're facing
and you
feel like there's
no way out, it's
beautiful in its own way that your
mind, your body,
your whole being, your spirit
has reached a point where
you can no longer
live the way you used to and
be the same
person you were.  This
has the potential to be a
turning point,
where a source of growth
, healing, renewal,
motivation to change
your life—all of these things
can arise from that
low point.  Only
when we become
truly honest with
ourselves and have the
courage to look
into the eyes of what we want to
change in ourselves do we
begin
to heal.  That's why
I want to see these
things as something quite
positive.  Although
for a long
time I felt
so much shame,
so much shame
associated with
the need to ask
for help,
feeling like I
needed to learn
to live in a new way.
At least for me, it
was very useful and
really helped
overcome some self-
doubt.  And I
still have a long way to go
, as you can
tell from my
latest video.  Well
, thank you all again
.  And I think what I'll
do with the rest of my
day: I'll put on my headphones
and go for a walk in the winter.    It's
so beautiful there now.
The snow is falling in very
thick flakes.
And, uh, I think I'll go
dance in the snow, have a
great time,
have fun with my
dog, and listen to
music.  There is one
Celtic-inspired band
that is quite
local to this
region of the US, and it's a trio of
very talented
women that I
recently
met.  I've
been asked many times on Instagram
what my favorite
music is.  90% of the time I
listen to
movie soundtracks or calm
, ambient music on
YouTube.  I really
like it.  It
helps my
creativity, especially
when I'm creating
art.  But I
also like to add
other very interesting
music here for entertainment,
to lift my
spirits and recharge my
energy.  And their
music is so
inspiring.  So I'm going to go
listen to it now.  And
as I run through this
winter's tale, I
will try to
continue to make
promises to myself, to
truly embrace
my positive
beliefs about
who I am, and not
let all
that negativity take
over.  So I'm sending
you so much love.
See you later.